Carolyn Riggs Bernardin Collection of Riggs & Lombard Photographs 6557 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Carolyn Riggs Bernardin Collection of Riggs & Lombard Photographs
1942
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Carolyn Riggs Bernardin
Riggs & Lombard
6557 P
1 folders
1 file folder.
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Photographs of the interior of the Riggs & Lombard machinery factory.
10062212
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 06, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 09, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Riggs & Lombard, Inc. was a Lowell, Massachusetts, company that manufactured, bought and sold textile and other machinery.
Scope and Contents
Includes photographs of the stock room, wood and steel erection floors, assembly floors, and machine shops. All photographs were taken by Marion Photographers, Lowell, Massachusetts, on January 13, 1942.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Machine parts; Machine shops; Textile machinery; Riggs & Lombard, Inc.
10062212
- Interior views (machine shop), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: New Stock Room, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Visible are all sorts of wheels, couplings, hoses, etc. Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
    Format: Black and White photograph.
  - Item 2: Wood Shop Erection Floor, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Wheels, lumber, ladders, etc. around the room; several male employees visible including two on the left who appear to be building a large wooden crate. Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 3: Old Steel Erection Floor, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Several male employees visible; steel machinery was apparently built on this floor. Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 4: Dryer Assembly and Erection, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts the area where dryers were assembled. Different lengths of metal stacked on floor; workbenches in rear where several male employees work. Note the bucket of sand on the pole labeled "Air Raid." Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 5: Machine Shop - Dryer Division, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Several male employees at work in the area. Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 6: Machine Shop A, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    A number of male employees are at work in the shop. Floor in the foreground is piled with wood shavings. This machine shop seems to be geared toward larger pieces, as opposed to machine shop B (see item 9 in this folde). Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 7: Wood Shop, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Several male employees are at work cutting or planing lumber. Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 8: New Steel Assembly Floor, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    One male employee in the foreground is hoisting sheets of steel; several others are at work in the background, including one who has tipped his welding mask up onto his head. Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 9: Machine Shop B, 1942; Black and White photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Several male employees at work. This machine shop seems to focus on smaller items, as opposed to machine shop A (see item 6 in this folder). Photo taken January 13, 1942. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.